双峰
第三季第十七集
你还好吗  戈登
You okay, Gordon?
我做不到  艾伯特
I couldn't do it, Albert.
我做不到
I couldn't do it.
你越老越心软了
You've gone soft in your old age.
什么
What?
我说  你越老越心软了
I said, "You've gone soft in your old age."
该硬的时候可没软过  伙计
Not where it counts, buddy.
敬局里
Here's to the Bureau.
-敬局里  -敬局里
- To the Bureau. - To the Bureau.
现在听我说
Now listen to me.
25年来
For 25 years,
我一直有件事瞒着你  艾伯特
I've kept something from you, Albert.
布里格斯少校消失前
Before he disappeared,
曾跟我和库柏分享过
Major Briggs shared with me and Cooper
他关于一种存在物的发现
his discovery of an entity,
一种极度消极的力量
an extreme negative force
在古代被称作乔德伊
called in olden times "Jowday."
随着时间推移  渐渐变成了"朱迪"
Over time, it's become "Judy."
布里格斯少校  库柏和我想了个计划
Major Briggs, Cooper, and I put together a plan
能带我们找到朱迪
that could lead us to Judy.
然后布里格斯少校就出事了
And then something happened to Major Briggs,
库柏也出事了
and something happened to Cooper.
菲利普·杰弗里斯
Phillip Jeffries,
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
那个已经不存在的人
who doesn't really exist anymore,
至少在常规意义上已经不存在了
at least not in the normal sense,
他在很久以前告诉我
told me a long time ago
翻译     苏小黛  Silence  TheWalkingNerd  詹木头
他在查这种存在
he was onto this entity,
然后他也消失了
and he disappeared.
翻译     Lynn_宁  Pang  吃冰棒  小酸奶
库柏最后跟我说的话是
Now, the last thing Cooper told me was...
校对     小酸奶
"要是我也像其他人一样消失了
"If I disappear like the others,
时间轴     今  啾啾
尽你最大能力去找我
do everything you can to find me.
我想要一石二鸟
I'm trying to kill two birds with one stone."
后期     8T
现在却出现了两个库柏
And now this thing of two Coopers.
总监     小酸奶
而且最近
And recently,
一个叫雷·门罗的收钱线人
a paid informant named Ray Monroe
发来一条隐晦的信息
sent a cryptic message
暗示我们在监狱里见到的库柏
indicating that the Cooper we met at prison
正在寻找做坐标
is looking for coordinates,
某个布里格斯少校的坐标
coordinates from a certain Major Briggs.
这个计划  艾伯特
This plan, Albert,
我不能告诉你
I couldn't tell you about,
很抱歉
and I'm sorry.
我明白
I understand.
我知道你明白  艾伯特
I know you understand, Albert,
然而我还是很抱歉
yet I'm still sorry.
我完全不知道这计划的进展是否正常
And I don't know at all if this plan is unfolding properly
因为我们现在应该
'cause we should have heard by now
收到亲爱的戴尔·库柏的消息了
from our dear Dale Cooper.
我是科尔
This is Cole.
我的海德利特工  长官
Agent Headley here, sir.
我们找到他了
We found him.
我们找到道格拉斯·琼斯了
We found Douglas Jones.
但是  我们不知道他在哪
But... we don't know where he is.
是我的手表停了
Has my watch stopped,
还是说这是马克斯兄弟中的一个
or is that one of the Marx Brothers?
这话是什么意思  海德利
What the hell does that mean, Headley?
床上没人
The bed is empty.
现在我的小队正在把所有东西发给你
My team is sending everything to you as we speak.
科尔局长  全都理清楚了
Director Cole, we got it all--
整个故事
the whole story.
电话那头是戈登·科尔吗
Is that Gordon Cole on the phone?
正是
Yes, it is.
-怎么了  -我有信息要给他
- Why? - I have a message for him.
来自道吉的信息
A message from Dougie.
你说什么
What's that?
这儿有个人...他说他有来自道格拉斯·琼斯的
Uh, there's a man here-- he says he has a message
信息要告诉你
for you from Douglas Jones.
那就告诉我吧
Well, give it to me.
请问你是戈登·科尔先生吗
Am I talking to Mr. Gordon Cole?
是我本人
Yes, you are.
道吉要我念这条信息给你
Well, Dougie wanted me to read you this--
"我要前往
"I am headed
杜鲁门警长那里
for Sheriff Truman's.
现在拉斯维加斯是2点53分
It's 2:53 in Las Vegas,
加起来等于10
and that adds up to a ten,
这数字代表完成"
the number of completion."
他写的就这些
That's all he wrote.
而先生你的大名是
And what is your name, sir?
布什内尔·穆林斯
Bushnell Mullins.
幸运之七保险公司
Lucky 7 Insurance.
我是他的上司
I'm his boss.
谢谢  穆林斯先生
Thank you, Mr. Mullins.
万分感激
Thank you very much.
我们俩都感谢你
And that makes two of us.
道吉就是库柏
Dougie is Cooper?
到底怎么回事
How the hell is this?
曾有人引爆道吉·琼斯的车
They blew up Dougie Jones' car.
还有位恶名昭彰的杀手
Then a notorious hit man
企图在他的公司外枪击他
tried to shoot him outside his place of business.
有人见到他在公司里
He's been spotted in the company
和两位犯罪集团首领在一起
of two organized-crime figures.
他把叉子插进了墙上的插座里...
He electrocuted himself by sticking a fork...
然后触电了
in a wall socket.
这就有点奇怪了  库柏也不干这种怪事
That's strange, even for Cooper.
应该又是一桩蓝玫瑰案
A Blue Rose case, most definitely.
他直到今下午还都在医院昏迷不醒
He was hospitalized in a coma until earlier this afternoon.
准备出发  我知道他要去哪里了
Pack it up! I know where he's going.
双峰镇警察局
终于安静了
Finally.
你个混蛋
You fucker.
混蛋
Fucker.
去你妈的
Fuck you.
这到底是怎么回事
What the hell is that?
不知道啊  伙计
No clue, mate.
"不知道啊  伙计"
"No clue, mate."
怀俄明州
Wyoming?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
您是叫本吗
Is your name Ben?
是的
Yes.
我们这有个伙计...
Got a guy here--
没带身份证  不肯告诉我们名字
no identification, won't give his name,
说他是你的哥哥
says he's your brother.
还说他用望远镜杀了人
Says his binoculars killed somebody.
那是我哥哥  杰瑞·霍恩
That's my brother, Jerry Horne.
他现在有什么指控吗
Is he charged with anything?
没有
No.
我会派人把他接回来的
I'll make arrangements to get him home.
你叫什么名字
What's your name again?
威廉姆斯警官  杰克逊镇警局
Sergeant Williams, Jackson Hole Police.
你可以寄点衣服来
And you can send clothes.
我们发现他的时候他是一丝不挂
When we picked him up, he was completely naked.
祝您度过美好的一天  先生
Have a good day, sir.
这是什么
What is this?
双峰警局
库柏特工
Agent Cooper,
是你吗
is that you?
库柏特工
Agent Cooper,
真是你啊
it is you.
我们正说到你
We were just talking about you.
你好  安迪
Hello, Andy.
怎么了
What's going on?
我觉得她想要说些什么
I think she's trying to say something.
大家都会很开心见到你的
Everyone's gonna be so happy to see you.
我也想见他们
And I would like to see them, too.
进来吧
Come on in.
我正准备把野餐篮拿进去
I was just taking this picnic basket in.
我们会煮一壶美味的咖啡
We'll make a fresh pot of coffee.
露西
Lucy.
露西  看谁来了
Lucy, look who's here.
-库柏特工  -你好  露西
- Agent Cooper! - Hello, Lucy.
我们正说到你
We were just talking about you.
我知道
So I understand.
杜鲁门警长  这位是戴尔· 库柏特工
Sheriff Truman, this is Special Agent Dale Cooper.
在沃利出世后我们都就没见过他了
We haven't seen him since before Wally was born.
杜鲁门警长
Sheriff Truman?
我是
I'm...
是弗兰克·杜鲁门警长  哈里的哥哥
Sheriff Frank Truman, Harry's brother.
-警长  -很高兴见到你
- Sheriff. - Nice to meet you.
进来坐下吧
Come into the office and sit down.
安迪
Andy?
坐吧  库柏特工
Have a seat, Agent Cooper.
要来杯咖啡吗
Would you like a cup of coffee?
不用了  谢谢
No, thanks.
我没事
I'm all right.
好的  我去告诉霍克你来了
Okay. I'm going to go tell Hawk you're here.
库柏
Cooper.
正是在下
In the flesh.
很重要  很重要
Very important. Very important.
霍克  你在吗
Hawk, are you down here?
这不是伟大的
If it isn't the great,
好警察  安迪副警长
good cop, Deputy Andy...
"伟大的好警察  安迪副警长"
"Great, good cop, Deputy Andy."
来拯救世界
...come to save the day.
"来拯救世界"
"Come to save the day."
你真是个孬种  安迪
You are such a pussy, Andy!
"你真是个孬种  安迪"
"You're a pussy, Andy."
现在怎么样
See how you like this,
就在我们俩...
right between--
双峰镇警察局长办公室  我是露西
Twin Peaks Sheriff's Station. This is Lucy speaking.
谁
Who?
你为什么回双峰镇来了
What brings you back to Twin Peaks,
库柏特工
Agent Cooper?
未竞之事
Unfinished business.
杜鲁门警长
Sheriff Truman?
什么事  露西
Yes, Lucy?
二号线有人找你
There's a phone call for you on line two,
灯在亮
the blinking light.
记下留言  露西
Take a message, please, Lucy.
这个电话很重要  警长
It's a very important phone call, Sheriff.
好吧  露西
All right, Lucy.
抱歉  库柏特工
Sorry, Agent Cooper.
我是杜鲁门
This is Truman.
哈里  我是库柏
Harry, it's Coop.
美国联邦调查局戴尔·库柏特工
Federal Bureau of Investigation, Special Agent Dale Cooper.
我是弗兰克·杜鲁门  哈里的哥哥
This is Frank Truman, Harry's brother.
你在哪
Where are you?
我们正在进入双峰市区
We're just entering Twin Peaks city limits.
有咖啡吗
Is the coffee on?
什么声音
What was that?
露西
Lucy.
我要把你们都带上楼
I've got to get you all upstairs.
我觉得他死了  库柏特工
I think this one's dead, Agent Cooper.
不要碰他  远离尸体
Don't touch him! Stay away from that body.
安迪
Andy...
我现在了解移动电话了
I understand cellular phones now.
怎么了
What the hell?
库柏特工说了不要碰那个尸体
Agent Cooper said don't touch that body.
但是那是库柏特工
But that is Agent Cooper.
不
No...
不是的
it's not.
安迪  他在哪里
Andy, where is he?
在这里
In here.
你是弗莱迪吗
Are you Freddie?
是的
That's right.
这就是我的命运
And this is me destiny.
弗莱迪
Freddie!
弗莱迪  起来
Freddie, get up!
用塑料袋
Catch you...
把你包起来
with my death bag.
我成功了吗
Did I do it?
你成功了  弗莱迪
You did it, Freddie.
给孙子们留一个
One for the grandkids.
弗兰克  你有大北方酒店的房间钥匙吗
Frank, do you have the room key to the Great Northern Hotel,
315室吗
315?
什么
What?
你怎么知道的
How do you know about--
布里格斯少校告诉我的
Major Briggs told me
杜鲁门警长会有这把钥匙
Sheriff Truman would have it.
这里发生了什么
What's going on around here?
我也正想这么问
Took the fucking words right out of my mouth.
加兰德·布里格斯少校
Major Garland Briggs.
博比  你父亲很清楚今天发生的事
Bobby, your father was well aware of what's going on here today.
到底怎么回事
What is going on?
很多年前  你父亲收集的情报
Many years ago, information your father gathered
让他结识了戈登·科尔主任
brought him together with Director Gordon Cole,
他现在也赶到了这里
who is here right on time.
戈登
Gordon.
小库
Coop.
这也是今天我们大家聚在一起的原因
And that's what's brought us to where we are today.
现在有些事有变
Now, there are some things that will change.
过去支配着未来
The past dictates the future.
来
Come on.
幸好我们做了这么多三明治
It's a good thing we made so many sandwiches.
弗兰克  代我向哈里问好
Frank... give my regards to Harry.
一定
Sure will.
戴安
Diane.
库柏...
Cooper...
唯一的那一个
the one and only.
你记得所有事吗
Do you remember everything?
记得
Yes.
我们都活在梦中
We live inside a dream.
希望能再见到大家...
I hope I see all of you again...
你们所有人
every one of you.
戈登
Gordon!
小库
Coop!
听着  我要进到这扇门里面去了
Now, listen, I'm going through this door.
别跟着我  你们谁也别跟来
Don't try to follow me, either of you.
我会想你的  小库
Be thinking of you, Coop.
谢幕时再见
See you at the curtain call.
穿过未来重重黑暗
Through the darkness of future past,
魔术师渴望重见光明
the magician longs to see.
在两个世界之间吟唱
One chants out between two worlds...
"与火同行"
"Fire... walk with me."
菲利普
Phillip?
请具体一点
Please, be specific.
日期
The date--
1989年2月23日
February 23, 1989.
我会找到的
I'll find it for you.
这里很滑
It's slippery in here.
很高兴再见到你  库柏
It's good to see you again, Cooper.
见到戈登帮我打声招呼
Say hello to Gordon if you see him.
他会记得非正式版本的
He'll remember the unofficial version.
在这里可以找到朱迪
This... is where you'll find Judy.
可能有个人...
There may be someone...
你问了我这个吗
Did you ask me this?
这里
There it is.
现在可以进去了
You can go in now.
库柏...
Cooper...
记住
...remember.
你怎么回事
What is wrong with you?
无处可去了  是吗  詹姆斯
There's no place left to go, is there, James?
想说什么就说吧
Say whatever you want.
我知道你爱我
I know you love me.
我爱你
And I love you.
我爱你  詹姆斯
I do love you, James.
让我们一起迷失吧
Let's get lost together.
该死
Shit.
什么
What?
他可能会想杀了你
He might try to kill you.
怎么了
What's wrong?
什么
What?
如果他发现了
If he finds out...
劳拉  怎么了
Laura, what's the matter?
博比杀了一个人
Bobby killed a guy.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
博比没有杀人
Bobby didn't kill anybody.
你想看吗
Do you want to see?
看什么
See what?
好
Right.
睁开你的眼睛  詹姆斯
Open your eyes, James.
你都不了解我
You don't even know me.
我有一些
There are things about me...
连唐娜都不知道的事
even Donna doesn't know me.
你的劳拉消失了
Your Laura disappeared.
现在只有我了
It's just me now.
劳拉
Laura.
这样呢  詹姆斯
What about this, James?
我觉得你现在想带我回家了
I think you want to take me home now.
劳拉
Laura!
不要
Don't!
上来
Come on!
不要
Don't!
Just don't!
我爱你  詹姆斯
I love you, James!
你是谁
Who are you?
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
等等
Wait.
我在梦里见过你
I've seen you in a dream.
在梦里
In a dream.
我们要去哪里
Where are we going?
我们要回家
We're going home.
去钓鱼了
Going fishing.